[
    {
        "numb": 1,
        "question": " Which term describes a company you do business with on a regular basis in a cooperative fashion, usually facilitated by IT systems?",
        "answer": "Alliance partner",
        "options": [
            "Alliance partner",
            "Information partnership",
            "Distribution chain",
            "B2B"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 2,
        "question": "Software designed to improve the performance of teams by supporting the sharing and flow of information is called a ?",
        "answer": "Collaboration system",
        "options": [
            "Social network system",
            "Group decision support system",
            "Team system",
            "Collaboration system"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 3,
        "question": "Processed ______________________ is also called ______________, while the most raw elements of facts and figures are known as ______________. ?",
        "answer": "Information; Knowledge; Data",
        "options": [
            "Data; Knowledge; Information",
            "Information; Data; Knowledge",
            "Information; Knowledge; Data",
            "Knowledge; Data; Information"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 4,
        "question": "The time dimension of information includes two aspects: having access to information when you need it and ________________. ?",
        "answer": "Having information that describes the appropriate time period",
        "options": [
            "Having access to information at the right moment in time",
            "Having information that describes the appropriate time period",
            "Having information about the most recent time period",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 5,
        "question": "Which of the following refers to using communications technologies to work in a location other than a central location (such as an office building) ?",
        "answer": "Telecommuting",
        "options": [
            "Wireless networks",
            "Business Intelligence",
            "Telecommuting",
            "Remote desktop"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 6,
        "question": "An information-literate knowledge worker will be able to ______________, while a technology-literate knowledge worker will always be able to _______________.?",
        "answer": "Act appropriately based on the information; know how and when to use technology",
        "options": [
            "Define what information they need; define what technology he/she needs",
            "Know how and where to obtain that information; create new technology when required",
            "Understand information before they even receive it; understand how technology affects him/her",
            "Act appropriately based on the information; know how and when to use technology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 7,
        "question": "Which dimension of information describes being able to access information from a hotel room??",
        "answer": " Location dimension",
        "options": [
            " Time dimension",
            " Location dimension",
            " Form dimension",
            " None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 8,
        "question": "Which of the following represents the flow of information between functional business units and work teams?",
        "answer": " Horizontal flow",
        "options": [
            " Upward flow",
            " Downward flow",
            " Horizontal flow",
            " Outward flow"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 9,
        "question": "The success of telecommuting depends on what?",
        "answer": " All of the above",
        "options": [
            " Suitability of profession",
            " Discipline",
            " Availability of technology",
            " All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 10,
        "question": "Which term describes electronic commerce conducted over a wireless device such as cell phone or PDA?",
        "answer": " M-Commerce",
        "options": [
            " CIS",
            " EIS",
            " Now economy",
            " M-Commerce"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 11,
        "question": "Which data manipulation tool allows you to graphically design the answer to your business question s?",
        "answer": " Query-by-example tools",
        "options": [
            " Report generators",
            " Application reports",
            " Data administration tools",
            " Query-by-example tools"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 12,
        "question": "Which data administration facility allows you to control who has access to what information and what type of access those people have?",
        "answer": " Security management facilities",
        "options": [
            " Concurrency control facilities",
            " Query optimization facilities",
            " Reorganization facilities",
            " Security management facilities"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 13,
        "question": "If you were a programmer and needed to view information as it was stored by the database, what type of database view would you see?",
        "answer": " Physical view",
        "options": [
            " Logical view",
            " Stored view",
            " Physical view",
            " Objective view"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 14,
        "question": "Which of the following functions plans for, oversees the development of, and monitors the information resource of an organization?",
        "answer": " Data administration",
        "options": [
            " Data administration",
            " Operational planning",
            " Strategic management",
            " Data manipulation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 15,
        "question": "A senior manager who analyzes internal and external information to analyze marketing campaigns and their affect on customer buying habits is using which type of application?",
        "answer": " Online analytical processing (OLAP)",
        "options": [
            " Enterprise resource planning (ERP)",
            " Online analytical processing (OLAP)",
            " Decision support systems (DSS)",
            " Geographic information systems (GIS)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 16,
        "question": "_____ is the gathering of input information, processing that information, and updating existing information to reflect the gathered and processed information?",
        "answer": " Online transaction processing (OLTP)",
        "options": [
            "File management systems (FMS)",
            " Online analytical processing (OLAP)",
            " Business intelligence (BI)",
            " Online transaction processing (OLTP)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 17,
        "question": "In a data warehouse, which data-mining tool would you use to quickly build reports without having to write programming code?",
        "answer": " Query-and-reporting tools",
        "options": [
            "Multidimensional analysis tools",
            " Query-and-reporting tools",
            " Artificial intelligence",
            " Application report generator"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 18,
        "question": "Which type of constraint ensures the quality of information in a relational database?",
        "answer": "Integrity constraint",
        "options": [
            "Integrity constraint",
            " Business constraint",
            " Environmental constraint",
            " Production constraint"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 19,
        "question": "_____ are the most essential and important quantifiable measures used in analytics initiatives to monitor success of a business activity?",
        "answer": " KPIs",
        "options": [
            "QBEs",
            " KPIs",
            " SQLs",
            " DPIs"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 20,
        "question": "A _____ is simply a copy of the information stored on a computer?",
        "answer": " Backup",
        "options": [
            "Duplicate",
            " Replica",
            " Backup",
            " Photocopy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 21,
        "question": "Which organizational function is responsible for the more technical and operational aspects of managing information repositories?",
        "answer": " Database administration",
        "options": [
            "Operational planning",
            " Information resource planning",
            " Strategic management",
            " Database administration"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 22,
        "question": "A _____ is a special form of a database that contains information gathered from operational databases for the purpose of supporting decision-making tasks?",
        "answer": " Data warehouse",
        "options": [
            "Data entry",
            " Data dictionary",
            " Data mine",
            " Data warehouse"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 23,
        "question": "If you were to perform a regression analysis, what type of data warehouse tool would it be?",
        "answer": " Statistical",
        "options": [
            "Multidimensional analysis",
            " Statistical",
            " Production analysis",
            " Hypercube"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 24,
        "question": "What is the most popular model for creating databases?",
        "answer": " Relational database model",
        "options": [
            "Ecological database model",
            " Object-oriented database model",
            " Relational database model",
            " Hierarchical database model"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 25,
        "question": "A database can contribute to organizational success by providing managers and decision makers with timely, accurate, and relevant information based on data?",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            " False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 26,
        "question": "A DBMS provides a single point of management and control over data resources?",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            " False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 27,
        "question": " The physical design of a database involves identifying relationships among the data items and grouping them in an orderly fashion?",
        "answer": " False",
        "options": [
            "True",
            " False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 28,
        "question": "Flat file databases do not use database models such as the relational model?",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            " False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 29,
        "question": "SQL is a visual approach to developing database queries or requests?",
        "answer": "False",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 30,
        "question": "Data warehouses allow managers to roll up to take detailed data and generate aggregate or summary reports?",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            " False"
        ]
    }
]